Guide to the Edmond Pauker Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Writings, 1925-51; Series I; 5.4; (14 boxes)
  - WORKS BY FERENC MOLNAR
    - Plays
      - The King's Maid
        - Typescript, carbon, corrected, "(1951 Version revised by the author)," two copies (Box 7, Folder 114-115)
        - Typescript, carbon, corrected, "(1951 Version revised by the author)", includes note by the author (Box 7, Folder 116)
        - Typescript, carbon, corrected, entitled The King's Handmaid, "literal translation" (Box 7, Folder 117)
        - Typescript, carbon, marked "Gloucester ve[r]sion", n.d. (Box 7, Folder 118)
        - Typescript, carbon, corrected, annotated: "This is NOT the final translation of Faragoh. The new additions have been translated by Miss E. BARCAY", n.d. (Box 7, Folder 119)
      - The Lawyer: printed version (Box 7, Folder 120)
        - Translated by György Halász, n.d.
      - Marshal: printed version, two copies, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 121)
      - Mima: printed version, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 122)
        Adaptation of Molnár's The Red Mill by David Belasco
      - Miracle in the Mountains
        - Typescript, corrected, marked "old", n.d. (Box 7, Folder 123)
        - Typescript, carbon, corrected, marked "old", "rough translation", n.d. (Box 7, Folder 124)
        - Complete stage version, rough translation, typescript, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 125)
        - Stage version, unrevised copy, typescript, carbon, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 126)
      - Mr. Somebody
        - Adaptation by Harold B. Brighouse, typescript, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 127)
        - Adaptation by Harold Brighouse, "As presented at: The Fine Arts Center Theater, Colorado Springs Colorado, August 4th, 1936", typescript, carbon, n.d. (Box 8, Folder 128)
      - Noah's Ark
        See also: Game of Hearts, Box 4, folder 82
        - Rough translation, typescript, carbon, corrected, n.d. (Box 8, Folder 129)
        - Typescript, carbon, corrected, n.d. (Box 8, Folder 130)
        - Typescript, carbons, corrected, 1943 Nov 20 (Box 8, Folder 131-134)
      - Olympia: English text by Sidney Howard, "First working draught May 5th, 1928. Revised - Sept. 15," typescript, carbon, corrected (Box 8, Folder 135)
      - Or Not to Be
        - In Hungarian, typescript, carbons, corrected, n.d. (Box 8, Folder 136-138)
        - Translated by Eva Barcay, typescript, carbons, corrected, n.d. (Box 8, Folder 139-140)
        - Translated by Eva Barcay, typescript, carbons, corrected, n.d. (Box 9, Folder 141-142)
        - Translated by Joan Dunlop, typescript, carbons, corrected (Box 9, Folder 143-145)
      - The Pastry-Baker's Wife ( Die Zuckerbäckerin ): typescript, carbon, n.d. (Box 9, Folder 146)
      - The Play's the Thing: adapted by P. G. Wodehouse, typescript, mimeograph, n.d. (Box 9, Folder 147)
      - Portrait of an Actor
        - "Based on the same author's Mars[h]al ," typescript, carbon, corrected, copyright 1949, 1951 (Box 9, Folder 148)
        - Typescript, mimeograph, n.d. (Box 9, Folder 149)
      - A Prologue to "King Lear": printed version, two copies, n.d. (Box 9, Folder 150-151)
        Translated by Louis Rittenberg
      - The Refuge: synopsis, typescript, 1943 Jul (Box 9, Folder 152)
      - Still Life: printed version, two copies, n.d. (Box 9, Folder 153-154)
        Translated by Sanford J. Greenburger
      - The Swan: printed version, n.d. (Box 9, Folder 155)
        English text by Benjamin F. Glazer
      - The Tale of the Wolf: "TV Version," outline and synopsis by Barbara Tolnai, typescript, carbon (Box 9, Folder 156)
      - There Is a Play Tonight
        - Act II, Scene I, holograph, n.d. (Box 9, Folder 157)
        - Typescript, carbon, corrected, n.d. (Box 9, Folder 158)
        - "First version," typescript, carbon, corrected, 1940 April 14 (Box 10, Folder 159)
        - Typescript, n.d. (Box 10, Folder 160)
        - Typescript, carbon, corrected and five typescript, carbons, uncorrected (Box 10, Folder 161-166)
      - The Violet
        - Translated by Arthur Richman, typescript, carbon, n.d. (Box 10, Folder 167)
        - Printed version, n.d. (Box 10, Folder 168)
          With: TLS, John Pauker, 1954 Dec 13
      - Wasser kommt aus den Bergen
        - Synopsis, typescript, carbon, in German, n.d. (Box 10, Folder 169)
      - Waxworks
        - English text by Arthur Richman, typescript, carbon, corrected, copyright 1942, 1948 Jan (Box 10, Folder 170)
        - English text by Arthur Richman, typescript, carbon, corrected, copyright 1942, 1949 Jan 11 (Box 10, Folder 171)
        - English text by Arthur Richman, typescript, carbon, corrected, copyright 1942, 1949 (Box 11, Folder 172)
        - "Vienna version (Akademie Theater)," English text by Arthur Richman, typescript, carbon, corrected, copyright 1942, 1949 (Box 11, Folder 173)
        - English text by Arthur Richman, typescript, carbon, copyright 1942, n.d. (Box 11, Folder 174)
      - The Wedding
        - Typescript, carbon, two copies, n.d. (Box 11, Folder 175-176)
        - In German, bound typescript, carbon, corrected (Box 11, Folder 177)
      - Wedding Day ( Nuptial Song )
        - Hungarian text, typescript, carbon, corrected, 1944 Sep 29 (Box 11, Folder 178)
        - First version, rough translation, typescript, carbon, corrected, 1944 Nov (Box 11, Folder 179)
        - "Rough translation of first version," typescript, carbon, corrected, 1945 (Box 11, Folder 180)
        - "Rough translation / first version," typescript, carbon, corrected, n.d. (Box 11, Folder 181)
      - The White Cloud: by Lawrence P. Bachman, based upon a play by Ferenc Molnár, typescript, n.d. (Box 11, Folder 182)
      - The Witch: printed version, n.d. (Box 11, Folder 183)
    - Stories
      - "Baron March"
        - Synopses, typescript, corrected and three typescript, carbons (Box 11, Folder 184-185)
        - Film treatment by Roza Pavlovits, in Hungarian, typescript, carbon, corrected, n.d. (Box 11, Folder 186)
      - "The Blue-Eyed Lady"
        - Film treatment, typescript, carbon, four copies, [1941?] (Box 12, Folder 187-188)
        - "My Story Almost Happened," essay on the writing of "The Blue-Eyed Lady," printed, published in Young Wings, 1942 (Box 12, Folder 189)
      - "Borromeo": typescript, carbon, corrected, n.d. (Box 12, Folder 190)
      - "The Coal Pilferers": translated by Michael Bálint, holograph, n.d. (Box 12, Folder 191)
      - "Disquiet Night"
        - Typescript, and two typescript carbons (Box 12, Folder 192)
        - Printed version, annotated, in Hungarian, n.d. (Box 12, Folder 193)
      - "The Gambler": translated by Michael Bálint, holograph, 1925 (Box 12, Folder 194)
      - "A gözoszlop": in Hungarian, holograph [in Molnár's hand] (Box 12, Folder 195)
      - "The Hat-Pin": typescript, carbon, n.d. (Box 12, Folder 196)
      - "The Key of the Third Drawer: From the Diary of a Jealous Man": translated by Michael Bálint, holograph, n.d. (Box 12, Folder 197)
      - "The Miraculous Stroke - A Modern Legend": translated by Michael Bálint, holograph (Box 12, Folder 198)
      - "Music"
        - Translated by Emil Lengyel, typescript, carbon, n.d. (Box 12, Folder 199)
        - Typescript, carbon, n.d. (Box 12, Folder 200)
      - "Princess Olga at the Funeral": translated by Michael Bálint, holograph, n.d. (Box 12, Folder 201)
      - "Props: From a Playwright's Notebook": typescript, carbon, corrected, n.d. (Box 12, Folder 202)
    - Other Works
      - "Children at War": synopses, typescript, carbon, corrected and typescript, carbons, four copies marked "film" or "film story" (Box 12, Folder 203-207)
      - "Cosmopolitan Theater" synopses: typescript, n.d. (Box 12, Folder 208)
        Synopses of Molnár's plays, novels, film treatments, and stories by an unidentified author
      - "Girl from Trieste: Adapted from the play by Ferenc Molnár" [radio script?]: typescript, carbon, corrected, n.d. (Box 12, Folder 209)
      - "Girl of My Dreams!" (film story)
        - Typescript, carbon, corrected, Hungarian text, two copies, 1941 May 4 (Box 12, Folder 210-211)
        - Typescript, carbon, annotated, two copies, n.d. (Box 12, Folder 212-213)
      - "Igen rövid fejezetek egy szinmüíró intim naplójából" (autobiographical sketch): in Hungarian, typescript, annotated, n.d. (Box 12, Folder 214)
      - "Jewels" (film story): in Hungarian, typescript, carbon, n.d. (Box 12, Folder 215)
      - "Love Makes Me Sick" (film story)
        Based on L. Pasternak's story "Daddy is a Wolf"
        - Hungarian text, typescript, carbon, corrected, 1945 Jan (Box 12, Folder 216)
        - Typescript, carbon, corrected, n.d. (Box 12, Folder 217)
      - "Mademoiselle Jourfix": synopsis, typescript, carbon, three copies, n.d. (Box 13, Folder 218)
      - "Material for a Soldier-story"
        - Typescript, carbon, Hungarian text, n.d. (Box 13, Folder 219)
        - Typescript, carbon, corrected, two copies, n.d. (Box 13, Folder 220-221)
      - "The Peculiar Relationship of the Artist and Money: Humorous Chapters from my Biography": typescript, carbon, corrected (Box 13, Folder 222)
        With: TLS, T. V. Ranck, Hearst Newspapers, 1928 Dec 20
      - The Smile of a Woman or Bill Duval
        - Synopses, typescript, carbon, corrected, Hungarian text, two versions, n.d. (Box 13, Folder 223-224)
        - Synopsis, typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 13, Folder 225)
        - Synopsis, typescript, carbon, corrected, n.d. (Box 13, Folder 226)
        - Outline, marked "film story," typescript, carbon, corrected, n.d. (Box 13, Folder 227)
      - Stella or Yvonne
        - Synopses entitled "Stella (Material for a Story)," typescript, carbon, four copies, n.d. (Box 13, Folder 228-231)
        - Synopses entitled "Yvonne," typescript, carbon, three copies, n.d. (Box 13, Folder 232-234)
        - Synopsis entitled "Scenario of a Comedy in Three Acts," typescript, carbon, corrected, n.d. (Box 13, Folder 235)
      - "Story II (Utilizing some of the elements of an old American short story)"
        - Typescript, carbon, in English, four copies, 1927 Aug 5 (Box 13, Folder 236-239)
        - Typescript, carbon, in Hungarian, n.d. (Box 13, Folder 240)
      - "Story III" ("Original Film Story")
        - Hungarian text, typescript, carbon, n.d. (Box 13, Folder 241)
        - Typescript and three carbons, 1927 Aug 5 (Box 13, Folder 242-245)
      - "Ein Thema für eine Filmgeschichte": Typescript, carbon, corrected, n.d. (Box 13, Folder 246)
      - "Two Boys and a Girl" ("film story"): Hungarian text, typescript, carbon (Box 13, Folder 247)
      - "The Wolf: Outline of an Original Film by Géza Herczeg Based on the Comedy by Ferenc Molnár": typescript, carbon, corrected, 1944 (Box 13, Folder 248)
  - WRITINGS OF OTHERS
    - Bryan, Maurie C.
      - Sixth Avenue: prologue and outline, typescript, carbon (Box 14, Folder 249)
    - Cobey, Herbert T.
      - "The Lady from Normandy": typescript, carbon (Box 14, Folder 250)
      - "A Story for Children": typescript, n.d. (Box 14, Folder 251)
    - Csergö, Hugó
      - "Hogyan lett Molnár Feriböl Molnár Ferenc": typescript, carbon, corrected, 1928 (Box 14, Folder 252)
    - Debrosse, Thomas
      - Hurricane Judith (novel):
        Translated by Alex. Harsányi
        - Synopsis, typescript, carbon, n.d. (Box 14, Folder 253)
        - Chapter headings, typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 14, Folder 254)
        - First chapter, typescript, carbon, corrected, n.d. (Box 14, Folder 255)
    - Elman, Irving
      - "Varsity U.S.A. at the University of Virginia": synopsis, typescript, carbon, n.d. (Box 14, Folder 256)
    - Halász, George
      - "Ferenc Molnár: The Man Behind the Monocle": typescript, carbon, corrected (Box 14, Folder 257)
    - Nádas, Sándor
      - "Budapest: The Town Whose Modern Literature was Born in a Cafe"
        - Typescript, carbon, corrected, n.d. (Box 14, Folder 258)
        - Typescript, carbon, corrected, three copies, n.d. (Box 14, Folder 259)
      - "The Famous Anecdotes of Ferenc Molnár": typescript, carbon, corrected, n.d. (Box 14, Folder 260)
      - "A Few Famous Sayings of Ferenc Molnár": typescript, carbon, 1940 Apr 12 (Box 14, Folder 261)
      - "Molnár Ferenc irodalmi asztala a budapesti Newyork Kávéhazban...," in Hungarian, typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 14, Folder 262)
- Business Files, 1898-1960; Series II; 14.6; (36 boxes)
  Series II contains two subseries, Client Files (Boxes 14-42) and General Files (Boxes 43-50).
  - CLIENT FILES
    The Client Files subseries (Boxes 14-42) is arranged alphabetically by author and then by title of the work. Materials that appear most frequently are contracts, correspondence, statements, and reviews and publicity, arranged in that order. Material of a general nature precedes that concerning specific titles. The literary genre of works other than plays is noted in parentheses after the title of the work. Contracts for the works of unidentified authors are placed at the end of the subseries.
    - Adler, Hans and Paul Frank
      - Fahrt nach Sorrent: contracts, 1930-31 (Box 15, Folder 263)
        Adapted by William A. Drake
      - Fourth From the Right: contract, 1934 Dec 27 (Box 15, Folder 264)
      - The Golden Ladder ( Der goldene Leiter ): contracts, 1930-36 (Box 15, Folder 265)
        Translated by W. L. B. Dunbar, adapted by Russell Janney
      - Première
        Adapted by Ernest Boyd and Alfred de Liagre, Jr.
        - Contracts, 1931-33 (Box 15, Folder 266)
        - Correspondence, 1956 (Box 15, Folder 267)
    - Anderson, Harold L.
      - Smell the Sweet Savor: contract, 1938 Mar 18 (Box 15, Folder 268)
    - Anderson, Virginia and Julius Anderson
      - A Young Man's Mother: contract, 1942 Sep 18 (Box 15, Folder 269)
    - Andrews, Charlton
      - Glimpses of the Moon: contract, 1935 May 23 (Box 15, Folder 270)
    - Anthony, Joseph
      - A Ship Comes In: contract, 1934 Jun (Box 15, Folder 271)
    - Asherman, Robert J.
      - The Dragon Slayer: contracts, 1955-58 (Box 15, Folder 272)
    - Bacher, John H.
      - The Happy Landmark: contract, 1942 Sep 10 (Box 15, Folder 273)
        Written under the name J. H. Overbrook
    - Balch, David Arnold
      - Drury Lane (formerly entitled Chesterfield ): contract, 1940 Nov 28 (Box 15, Folder 274)
    - Bardoly, Louis S. and Adelyn Bushnell
      - Barbara: contract, 1938 Jun 21 (Box 15, Folder 275)
    - Barrymore, Elaine
      - Untitled biography of John Barrymore: contract, 1950 Jun 8 (Box 15, Folder 276)
    - Baum, Vicki
      - Correspondence: general, 1952-58 (Box 15, Folder 277)
      - Divine Drudge: statements, 1952 Nov 10 (Box 15, Folder 278)
      - Grand Hotel: statements, 1956-58 (Box 15, Folder 279)
      - Pariser Platz 13: contracts, 1930-31 (Box 15, Folder 280)
        Translated by William Drake
      - Photographs, 1931-32 (Box 15, Folder 280a)
    - Baum, Vicki and Benjamin F. Glazer
      - Saturday Night: contracts, 1939 (Box 15, Folder 281)
    - Begovic, Milan
      - Saint Wench ( Gottes Mensch ): contracts, 1930-38 (Box 15, Folder 282)
        Adapted by John Colton
    - Behrman, S. N.
      - Biography: contract, 1935 Dec (Box 15, Folder 283)
    - Békessy, Imre
      - Contract: general, 1941 Sep 24 (Box 15, Folder 284)
    - Benatzky, Ralph
      - Der König mit dem Regenschirm: contracts, 1937 Dec (Box 15, Folder 285)
        Production contract with Otto Preminger
    - Benedict, Kingsley and Jeannette Benedict
      - Charlotte Corday: contract, 1937 Aug 10 (Box 15, Folder 286)
    - Bergquist, Lillian
      - Correspondence: general, 1958 (Box 15, Folder 287)
      - Real Situation: contract, 1945 April 3 (Box 15, Folder 288)
    - Bernauer, Rudolf and Rudolf Oesterreicher
      - The Second Life ( Das zweite Leben ): contract, 1930 Aug (Box 15, Folder 289)
    - Berns, Julie and Irving Elman
      - Uncle Willie
        - Contracts, 1956-57 (Box 15, Folder 290)
        - Correspondence, 1956-58 (Box 15, Folder 291-292)
        - Statements, 1956-58 (Box 15, Folder 293)
        - Programs, 1956 (Box 15, Folder 294)
        - Publicity, 1956-57 (Box 15, Folder 295)
    - Bernstein, Henry
      - The Claw ( La griffe ): contract, 1940 Aug (Box 15, Folder 296)
    - Bernstein, Hillel and Sylvia Bernstein
      - "The Big Lie" (story): contract, 1943 May 12 (Box 15, Folder 297)
      - "Eighty Days to Oklahoma" (screenplay): contracts, 1943 Sep (Box 15, Folder 298)
    - Berstl, Julius
      - Dover-Calais: correspondence, 1954 (Box 15, Folder 299)
      - Napoleon der Zweite: contracts, 1930-31 (Box 15, Folder 300)
    - Bethlen, Margaret and Patsy Ruth Miller
      - The Victor: contract, 1947 Feb 10 (Box 15, Folder 301)
    - Birabeau, André
      - Dame Nature: contracts, 1940 Jan 22 (Box 15, Folder 302)
        Adapted by Patricia Collinge
    - Birinski, Leo
      - Clouds Over the Continent: contract, 1937 Dec 10 (Box 15, Folder 303)
    - Birmingham, George A.
      - Burglars and Send for Dr. O'Grady: contracts, 1924 Feb 11 (Box 15, Folder 304)
    - Biró, Lajos
      - Hotel Imperial: contract, 1935 Jul 30 (Box 15, Folder 305)
    - Biró, Sári
      - Contracts: general, 1939 (Box 15, Folder 306)
    - Bittner, Georg and Paul Frank
      - Magic Fire: contract, 1941 Jun 16 (Box 15, Folder 307)
    - Blinick, Augusta
      - Ready to Wear: contracts, 1939 May 25 (Box 15, Folder 308)
    - Bloch, Bertram
      - Joseph: contract, 1930 Apr 1 (Box 15, Folder 309)
        Adapted by [G. A.] Sil-Vara
    - Blum, Edwin Harvey
      - Backwash: contracts, 1936 (Box 15, Folder 310)
    - Blume, Bernhard
      - Gelegenheit macht Diebe: contracts, 1932 May 20 (Box 15, Folder 311)
    - Blumenthal, Oscar and Gustav Kadelburg
      - White Horse Inn ( Im weissen Rossl )
        Title varies. Translated by Sydney Rosenfeld
        - Contracts, 1898-1933 (Box 15, Folder 312-314)
        - Correspondence, 1955-57 (Box 15, Folder 315-316)
    - Bodeen, Dewitt
      - Bunner Sisters: contracts, 1946-50 (Box 15, Folder 317)
        Based on the novel by Edith Wharton
      - Harvest of Years: contracts, 1946-47 (Box 15, Folder 318)
    - Boehm, David
      - The Big Putsch: contract, 1938 May 25 (Box 17, Folder 319)
        For adaptation by Otis Chatfield Taylor
    - Bois, Curt and Max Hansen
      - Dienst am Kunden: contract, 1931 Nov 12 (Box 17, Folder 320)
    - Boretz, Allen
      - Contracts: general, 1935, 1940 (Box 17, Folder 321)
      - Correspondence: general, 1956 (Box 17, Folder 322)
      - As the Twig: contract, 1934 Jun 26 (Box 17, Folder 323)
    - Boretz, Allen and Ned Glass
      - Schoolteacher: contract, 1934 Jun 4 (Box 17, Folder 324)
    - Boros, Ladislas and Martin M. Goldsmith
      - Untitled book: "biographical fiction about Hortense Schneider and Jacques Offenbach": contracts, 1943-1944 (Box 17, Folder 325)
    - Boross, Elemér
      - Forgószél: contract, 1935 Sep 30 (Box 17, Folder 326)
        For adaptation by Andor De Soos
      - Vakablak: contracts, 1929 (Box 17, Folder 327)
        Incl: contract for adaptation by David Belasco
    - Bostick, Jack
      - Companion Piece
        - Contract, 1951 Jan 8 (Box 17, Folder 328)
        - Statements, 1951 (Box 17, Folder 329)
    - Branch, Houston
      - American Holiday: contract, 1935 Sep 26 (Box 17, Folder 330)
    - Branch, Houston and Charles Wakefield Cadman
      - The Splendid Hour: contracts, 1935-37 (Box 17, Folder 331)
    - Breene, Bess
      - Roller Shades: contract, 1934 Jun 18 (Box 17, Folder 332)
    - Breuer, Kurt and ---- Frieser-Zwerenz
      - Love Coach ( Die Liebeskutsche ): contract, 1930 (Box 17, Folder 333)
        For translation by W. L. Barre Dunbar
    - Brown, Beth
      - Correspondence: general, 1954-57, n.d. (Box 17, Folder 334)
        See also: Oversize, Box 52, folder 1258
      - Applause (novel): contracts, 1928-56 (Box 17, Folder 335)
      - "Bad Actor" (story): contract, 1933 Dec 22 (Box 17, Folder 336)
      - Ballyhoo (book): contracts, 1930, 1954 (Box 17, Folder 337)
      - For Men Only (novel): contracts, 1935 May 1 (Box 17, Folder 338)
      - "Red Velvet" (story): contracts, 1928-29 (Box 17, Folder 339)
    - Bruckner, Ferdinand
      - Krankheit der Jugend: contract, 1932 Nov 30 (Box 17, Folder 340)
        For adaptation by Patrick Kearney
    - Bruff, Nancy
      - Beloved Woman (novel): contract, 1949 Jan 25 (Box 17, Folder 341)
    - Bús-Fekete, László (Ladislas)
      - Contracts: general, 1936-39 (Box 17, Folder 342)
      - Correspondence: general, 1954-56 (Box 17, Folder 343)
      - Birthday ( Geburtstag ): contracts, 1937-38 (Box 17, Folder 344)
        For adaptation by Joseph Mankiewicz
      - Change Partners: contracts, 1939 (Box 17, Folder 345)
      - Ladies and Gentlemen
        Adapted by Charles MacArthur and Ben Hecht
        - Contracts, 1938-47 (Box 17, Folder 346)
        - Statements, 1951 Feb 14 (Box 17, Folder 347)
      - The Lady Has a Heart ( Jean )
        - Contracts, 1936-37 (Box 17, Folder 348)
          Incl: contract with Otto Preminger
        - Statements, 1937-39 (Box 17, Folder 349)
      - Porcupine: contracts, 1937-46 (Box 17, Folder 350)
    - Bús-Fekete, László (Ladislas) and Mary Helen Fay
      - Embezzled Heaven
        Based on a novel by Franz Werfel
        - Contracts, 1941-58 (Box 18, Folder 351)
        - Correspondence, 1953-54 (Box 18, Folder 352-354)
      - Moonlight Mazourka: contract, 1944 Aug 31 (Box 18, Folder 355)
      - Think It Over: contracts, 1944 (Box 18, Folder 356)
      - Tryout in Boston: contracts, 1942-44, n.d. (Box 18, Folder 357)
    - Bús-Fekete, Fay, and Sheldon
      Authors' full names: László (Ladislas), Bús-Fekete, Mary Helen Fay, and Sydney Sheldon
      - Star in the Window: contracts, 1944 (Box 18, Folder 358)
    - Bushnell, Adelyn
      - Contracts: general, 1934-35 (Box 18, Folder 359)
      - Devilish Delight: contract, 1939 Nov 20 (Box 18, Folder 360)
      - Glory ( Gram ): contracts, 1934-36 (Box 18, Folder 361)
      - It's Your Own Funeral: contracts, 1934 Mar (Box 18, Folder 362)
      - Ready He Stands: contracts, 1938-39, n.d. (Box 18, Folder 363)
    - Cammerlohr, Franz
      - Autos machen Leute ( Diktator ): contracts, 1930 Aug 1 (Box 18, Folder 364)
    - Carpenter, Helen
      - This Way Out: contract, 1942 Dec 10 (Box 18, Folder 365)
    - Chaine, Pierre
      - L'Heure H...: contracts, 1937-38 (Box 18, Folder 366)
        Incl: contracts for adaptation by Jerome Chodorov and Joseph Fields
    - Chlumberg, Hans
      - Das Bläue von Himmel: contracts, 1929-30 (Box 18, Folder 367)
        Incl: contract for translation by W. L. B. Dunbar
      - Wunder um Verdun: contracts, 1930-31 (Box 18, Folder 368)
    - Chodorov, Edward
      - Contracts: general, 1943-56 (Box 18, Folder 369)
      - Legal and financial documents, 1951-58 (Box 18, Folder 370)
      - Correspondence: general, 1952-54 (Box 18, Folder 371-373)
      - Correspondence: general, 1955 (Box 18, Folder 374)
        Incl: James Mason
      - Correspondence: general, 1956 (Box 18, Folder 375)
        Incl: Lawrence Olivier, Toby Rowland
      - Correspondence: general, 1957 (Box 19, Folder 376-378)
        Incl: Cheryl Crawford, Jose Quintero (Circle in the Square), Darryl Zanuck
      - Correspondence: general, 1958 (Box 19, Folder 379)
        Incl: Armina Marshall (Theatre Guild), Toby Rowland, Alfred de Liagre, Jr.
      - Statements: general, 1952-59 (Box 19, Folder 380)
      - The Annotator
        - Contracts, 1955-57 (Box 19, Folder 381)
          For Chodorov's dramatization of the novel of this title by Roger Lubbock and Alan Keen
        - Statements, 1956 (Box 19, Folder 382)
      - The Backward Bride
        - Contracts, 1955-57 (Box 19, Folder 383)
          For Chodorov's dramatization of the novel of this title by Aubrey Menen
        - Statement, 1957 Jun 25 (Box 19, Folder 384)
      - City Without Jews: contracts, 1933-35 (Box 19, Folder 385)